<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-event library="Select">
	<name>user-select</name>
	<summary>A user action will cause items to be selected in the table</summary>
	<since>1.2.0</since>

	<type type="function">
		<signature>function( e, dt, type, cell, originalEvent )</signature>
		<parameter type="object" name="e">
			jQuery event object
		</parameter>
		<parameter type="DataTables.Api" name="dt">
			DataTables API instance
		</parameter>
		<parameter type="string" name="type">
			Item type that will be selected. This can be `-string row`, `-string column` or `-string cell`.
		</parameter>
		<parameter type="DataTables.Api" name="cell">
			A `dt-api cell()` result for the cell that the event was activated by.
		</parameter>
		<parameter type="object" name="originalEvent">
			The original event that was generated by the browser when the end user activated the selection listening event.
		</parameter>
		<scope>HTML table element</scope>
	</type>

	<description>
		This event is triggered _before_ items are selected based on an interaction with the table by the end user (typically clicking on a cell in the table).

		This event is **cancellable** - i.e. using `e.preventDefault()` or `return false;` in the event handler will stop Select from performing any further actions for the selection. This can be useful for cases where you don't want certain items in the table to cause item selection (for example you might have images which perform some other action and should not activate row selection).

		Note that this event will not be triggered when the API methods for item selection are used (e.g. `se-api row().select()`). It will only be triggered by an end user action defined by `se-init select.selector`.

		If you wish to make a row totally unselectable, use the `-init select.selectable` option.

		Additionally, as with all DataTables emitted events, this event is triggered with the `dt` namespace. As such, to listen for this event, you must also use the `dt` namespace by simply appending `.dt` to your event name (this is done automatically when using `dt-api on()` and `dt-api one()`). 
	</description>

	<example title="Prevent item selection when clicking on an image"><![CDATA[
var table = new DataTable('#myTable', {
	select: true
});

table.on('user-select', function (e, dt, type, cell, originalEvent) {
	if (originalEvent.target.nodeName.toLowerCase() === 'img') {
		e.preventDefault();
	}
});
]]></example>

	<related>-init select.selectable</related>
	<related>-api select.selectable()</related>
</dt-event>
