<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-option library="Select">
	<name>select.style</name>
	<summary>Set the selection style for end user interaction with the table</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<default value="os"/>

	<type type="string">
		<description>
			This option can take one of the following values:

			* `-string api` - Selection can only be performed via the API
			* `-string single` - Only a single item can be selected, any other selected items will be automatically deselected when a new item is selected
			* `-string multi` - Multiple items can be selected. Selection is performed by simply clicking on the items to be selected
			* `-string os` - _Operating System_ (OS) style selection. This is the most comprehensive option and provides complex behaviours such as ctrl/cmd clicking to select / deselect individual items, shift clicking to select ranges and an unmodified click to select a single item.
			* `-string multi+shift` - a hybrid between the `os` style and `multi`, allowing easy multi-row selection without immediate de-selection when clicking on a row. 
		</description>
	</type>

	<description>
		Select provides a number of different built in ways that an end user can interact with the selection of items in the table, which is controlled by this parameter (and `s-api select.style()` after initialisation).

		The default mode of operation is based on the selection of files in modern operating systems with the ctrl/cmd and shift keys can be user to provide complex operations.

		Note that while the `-string api` option disables item selection via Select's built in event handler, it is quote possible to use the API to still provide the end user with the ability to select / deselect items based on your own event handlers.
	</description>

	<example title="Disable end user selection via Select's click event handler"><![CDATA[

$('#example').DataTable( {
	select: {
		style: 'api'
	}
} );

]]></example>

	<example title="Enable selection with single item selection only"><![CDATA[

$('#example').DataTable( {
	select: {
		style: 'single'
	}
} );

]]></example>
</dt-option>