<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-api library="Select">
	<name>select.style()</name>
	<summary>Get / set the style by which the end user can select items in the table</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<type type="function">
		<signature>select.style()</signature>
		<returns type="string">
			The current selection style, this will be one of `-string api`, `-string single`, `-string multi` or `-string os`.

			Note that if multiple tables are defined in the API's context, only the selection style of the first table will be returned.
		</returns>
		<description>
			Get the current selection style applied to the table. 
		</description>
	</type>

	<type type="function">
		<signature>select.style( set )</signature>
		<parameter type="string" name="set">
			Selection style to set - this must be one of `-string api`, `-string single`, `-string multi` or `-string os`.
		</parameter>
		<returns type="DataTables.Api">
			DataTables API instance for chaining.
		</returns>
		<description>
			Set the table's selection style.
		</description>
	</type>

	<description>
		Select has four different modes of operation for end user selection of items in the table:

		* `-string api` - Selection can only be performed via the API - this means that selection is disabled unless you use the API
		* `-string single` - Only a single item can be selected, any other selected items will be automatically deselected when a new item is selected
		* `-string multi` - Multiple items can be selected. Selection is performed by simply clicking on the items to be selected
		* `-string os` - _Operating System_ (OS) style selection. This is the most comprehensive option and provides complex behaviours such as ctrl/cmd clicking to select / deselect individual items, shift clicking to select ranges and an unmodified click to select a single item.

		Each of these options can be used with the three table items that can be selected (`se-api select.items()`).
	</description>

	<example title="Let the user select items using the _os_ selection style"><![CDATA[
var table = new DataTable('#myTable');

table.select.style('os');
]]></example>

	<related>s-init select.style</related>
</dt-api>